Controlling when and by whom deferred
income and expenses can be posted to the
general ledger.
Hi.
Today we're going to show you how you
can determine when it's allowed to post
to the general ledger for deferred
income and expenses.
A quick note on deferrals.
In Business Central, you can use
deferral templates to set up how income
or expenses should be deferred, meaning
into the future.
Let's take a quick look at a deferral
template.
Here you see a deferral template which
is set up to capture my income in a
straight line over the next six
accounting periods, which is six months
in my case.
This means this will create future GL
postings when I post an invoice set up
with this deferral template.
That also means I might not want to
allow everyone to do so.
First of all, it's important to know
that if I go to the general ledger
setup, I can control
which rules for deferral postings apply
for my entire company.
So here you see two fields defining the
window for when it's allowed to post
deferrals to the general ledger.
This is set up to capture the year of
2023.
But since I want to post an invoice into
the future now and capture revenue over
the next six months,
I might want to enable one user to do
that.
So I can do that with user setup.
Here you see that Carlos is actually
able to post deferrals into the future
all the way through June in 2024.
So this is a great way where you can
determine who can post and when to the
general ledger for deferrals.
Thank you for watching.